[Music]
the stoa
is a digital campfire where we cohere in
dialogue
about what matters most at the knife's
edge of what's happening now
beautiful people welcome to the store
donna do you want to open up
or you're mute can you mute yourself yes
you can
no oh there we go there you go
do you want to open it up and then give
the stoa opening and everything
welcome to the stoa
the stoa is the digital campfire
where we cohere and dialogue about what
matters most at the knife's edge
oh my gosh the first line of that song
that you played peter was i want to hold
the hand inside of you
that is so perfect
oh so welcome everyone
oh gosh gosh i i recognize almost
everybody
okay the people that um
don't have their video on are you able
to put your video on
it'll be really nice to see you and say
hi and
it's nice to look to be able to look at
you when we're doing practice
so if you can put your video on please
do
if not it's okay hi thank you
okay great
so i'm donna um
and i'm going to lead us in inner
subjective practice
um so some of you were here last month
when i did this we just called it um
inner subjective partner practice and
peter said oh we have to change the name
we have to have something more jazzy
so if you were here last time just raise
your hand so i know
who's here
okay all right
well i know that a lot of you are
familiar with this type of practice
tonight will be very interesting
so why don't we um just
all come in here together
notice how you are right now how you
find yourself coming to this meeting
um sort of do a
personal check-in
i just want to look at you all i'm so
happy
so notice your breathing
if you have short breaths or if you're
feeling kind of relaxed and tired i was
very tired
about five minutes ago until i saw all
your faces
just breathe together
you can close your eyes if you'd like
you can keep them open
notice if there's any emotions running
through your body
check in with your body
if there's anything you need to do to
bring yourself fully
here go ahead and do that now so that we
can give each other our full attention
comfortable
we'll be together for the next hour
so welcome the complexity of who you are
too
i'm not just my body i'm also my
personality
my culture my emotions
my spirit
my love my ideas
and my breakfast
so many things go into making who we are
and how we show up right now
and then return to the air passing
through your body
let your breathing remind you that we
are in exchange
with the atmosphere of the planet
with all of life
puppies the trees
and with each other
still have that image that we're holding
or holding hands inside of each other
and let yourself relax into this
exchange
our breathing is a testament to the fact
that life
requires that we stay in exchange if we
try to stop that exchange would die
have to keep breathing
staying in the exchange
it takes more energy to hold up our
boundaries anyway
you don't have to make the exchange
happen
it's already happening it's always
available
we're just focusing on it and becoming
conscious of it
very good i think we're all here now
so in less than 12 hours i will be
sitting on the bank of a lake
with a great blue heron as i do most
mornings
he sits on a branch that's fallen into
the water
and it sticks out of the water and he's
there every day
and i sit about 20 feet away from him
he watches for the fish and i watch him
it's the most amazing thing when he
catches a fish his whole body plunges
into the water
he comes back up in this he has this
fish in his mouth that
seems way too big to fit down his throat
and i can actually see the fishtail like
flopping
in his throat and the outline of the
fish
as it just kind of goes down slowly
then he does this amazing thing he he's
holding on to the
branch with his feet and
with the the fish stuck in his throat
he turns his whole body upside down and
he dips his beak into the water to
to grab some water and then and he
doesn't fall over
and he comes back up and he and he takes
a drink and then slowly the fish goes
down
this whole process takes about five
minutes or so
very familiar with it he's my morning
friend
and then he um he wipes his beak off
on against the side of the branch
then he flies away
this morning when i was out there there
was this nice
breeze it was making these ripples
across the top of the water
and i remembered something a teacher
told me years ago
he said that there's a holy wind that
blows through you
and i used to think that that was god
and i'm not sure what to call it anymore
but
i know that even though you and i are
not the same
that that same holy wind that blows
through me
blows through you
what moves through me moves through you
on some level we're interconnected
and interdependent and for me that's
what these intersubjective practices are
about
and i know that i know that that wind
travels through both through all of us
and i wonder how i know that
there's so many things that i don't know
and so many things that i can't make
sense of
in our world but that
i know
and i know that the way that we are with
each other matters
as if the wind feels it too the way we
interact with each other
these inner subjective practices can be
that simple
you and me and the wind that blows
through us
um rebel wisdom recently released a
video called
the evolving conversation with john
varvakey and peter limberg
you may have seen that and it's
there's one one part in there um john's
john's talking about he's doing this
project and
um i will butcher this peter but um
he's doing this project where he's
blending socratic dialogue with circling
in the exploration of wisdom something
like that
and in this video john proposes
that rather than being motivated by
curiosity in our inner subjective
practices
that we should invoke wonder we should
be invoking wonder
and he says that wonder is where you are
opening to the space
where you're confronting mystery being
in the unknown together
he says you're calling out into question
yourself
and your world so that they both can
undergo a restructuring of identity
he says wonder can deepen into awe
which has the powerful ability to pull
people beyond their egocentrism
so we're going to try out john's
proposal today
so we're not going to go into the
dialogues around wisdom
but we're going to see if we can
participate and wonder together
and actually go into the wonder
participatory
knowing of wonder as as he says where
where you you know something by becoming
it and interacting with it
so as we sit together in all of our
complexity
i want you to include your in your
awareness
the deepest uh most sacred
part of yourself that you can locate
it has nothing to do with the roles that
you play in life
and it has nothing to do with your to-do
list
or your future accomplishments your
plans for conquest
but it is it's that greater depth
that seems to go on forever like the
wind
you can't hold on to it you can only be
in the movement of it
hopefully this invokes a sense of wonder
about who we even are
and what happens when two people turn
toward each other and
open from this deepest place
it's like the mystery that you are even
to yourself
so if you have your eyes closed you can
go ahead and open them
see if you can make eye contact with a
few of us
history to mystery
sacred to sacred
and as two fragrances can occupy the
same space
we say there's room in me for you
these practices can be very intimate
i think that's a good thing
so in our breakout rooms we're going to
let wonder lead
i think we're going to do this in two
sections
so our first breakout will have a moment
of silence
with your partner just be with each
other
however you experience the
interconnectedness and the flow between
you and just sort of settle into each
other in that exchange
and then after one minute i'll send a
broadcast and it says now the
first person speaks and one person is
going to explore for five minutes
beginning with i wonder so that's how
you're going to speak
begin your sentences or your questions
with i wonder
and then the second person will go
see if you can listen inside of the
wonder of your partner
you're listening and then we're gonna
come back here to the main room
and we'll see how that was and then
we'll go back out for another section
another part and i think we're good on
timing
okay so peter and my host